californiaprogressreport.com 2011-10-04

# Privacy Policy | California Progress Report

The California Progress Report and its owner, the Consumer Federation of California Education Foundation, respect your privacy. We do not collect personally identifiable information on our web site unless you choose to give it to us via an e-mail message, an online form, by responding to an action alert, by submitting an article or comment, or by making an on-line contribution.

The California Progress Report, the Consumer Federation of California Education Foundation and the Consumer Federation of California share certain resources, including website resources. The California Progress Report, the CFC and the CFC Education Foundation may share information with each other regarding persons who contact any of these organizations’ websites.

The California Progress Report **does not** share any personally identifiable information about individuals who contact us, except as outlined in this policy, and in the privacy policy of the Consumer Federation of California and the Consumer Federation of California Education Foundation, which is posted on the CFC’s website ([www.consumercal.org](http://www.consumercal.org/ "Consumer Federation of California")).

Some features of this website may ask for your name, address, email address and other contact information. The information we collect is intended to help us improve the content of our site; to send you email updates and notices, including solicitations of donations to the California Progress Report, the Consumer Federation of California Education Foundation or the Consumer Federation of California; to process your on line donations; to provide you with accurate information about your elected and appointed officials; or as a requirement for writers to post articles and for readers to post comments on the website.

We may on occasion refer persons who contact us with an inquiry to a government agency or other individuals or organizations that might be of assistance provided you specifically authorize us to share your contact information. Information that you provide us is stored on a database maintained by a contractor, with restrictions on sharing it with third parties. Information from on line donors is shared with our on line merchant account transaction processor and with our bank, with restrictions on sharing it with third parties.

On occasion, we may conduct a coordinated campaign with one or more allies. In a coordinated campaign, we may share with allies who direct their correspondents to an action alert on our website the names and email addresses of individuals who took action using our website. We would disclose in an action alert the names of allies participating in a coordinated campaign.

**We do not otherwise sell, rent, share or otherwise disclose personally identifiable information regarding persons who contact us,** unless required by law or for the limited purpose of processing your transaction.

Our web server may place cookies on your computer containing information you have given us (for example, your address or zip code). These cookies are designed to allow us to provide you more focused information on issues (for example, information on how to contact your lawmakers, based on your address or zip code). These cookies are nonessential to the working of the site, and you may block them from being placed on your computer without any loss of site functionality.

Our web server also collects anonymous information that we use to help diagnose problems with our server and to track web traffic on our site. E-mail addresses and other personally identifiable information regarding visitors are not available to us, unless you choose to contact us via e-mail or online form.

If you have any questions or concerns about this privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email: [editor@californiaprogressreport.com](mailto:editor@californiaprogressreport.com "email us")
